

Kolja Marius Krueckmeyer

Germany

Education

Qualifications Master in Computer Science

University of Luebeck, Germany

Thesis Title: Comparison of the Struts framework and the Google Web Toolkit to implement a web application using the example of MarathonNet project, 2007

English Very Good Languages German Fluent

French Basic

Professional experience

Profile

As a full-stack software developer and IT architect, I have over 12 years of experience in various clients engagements. I provide strong analytical and logical thinking skills as well as a conscientious and structured way of working. I offer deep knowledge in the design and implementation of system architectures and the development of web applications, Java, JEE, databases, front- and backend development and agile methodologies.

Please see my assignment history for further details.

Key Skills

- Software engineering in Java and JEE
- Softwarearchitecture
- web development
- agile software development, test-driven development
- ScrumMaster PSM I
- analytical and logical thinking skills
- Industry knowledge: E-Commerce, Print Industry, Automotive
- microservices
- DevOps
- Continuous Integration/Delivery
- Kubernetes, Docker
- AWS
- Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript
- JPA/Hibernate, databases (DB2, Oracle, MySQL), SQL, MongoDB
- Application Server: JBoss/Wildfly, Tomcat, Websphere Portal Server
- Spring
- Apache Kafka

Key Courses and Training

- JEE development with JBoss Basic knowledge
- JavaScript and AJAX basic & advanced knowledge
- ScrumMaster PSM I
- various soft skill seminars
- Project Management Fundamentals
- Installation and Administration WebSphere Portal Server on Linux
- Architectural Thinking Course
- Watson Cognitive Bootcamp
- Machine Learning (University Stanford)
- further achievements: https://www.youracclaim.com/user/kolja-kruckmeyer

Career History 03/2014 - To date

IBM Deutschland GmbH, Germany

Page 1 of 4 Date: 18-Dec-2020



IT Specialist/Architect

IBM Software Group Services for Collaboration

01/2011 - 02/2014

Materna GmbH, Germany

Software developer

Development and consulting for a company in the field of e-commerce

08/2010 - 10/2010

Company in the field of IT services Software developer and project leader

Development, maintenance and project management for various web applications

02/2008 - 07/2010

Ferchau Engineering, Germany

Software developer

Development and consulting in various customer projects as a software developer and project leader

Assignment History

05/2019 - To date

20 months

Phoenix Contact

Projekt CRISP

<u>Project Description:</u> Phoenix Contact is the global market leader and innovation leader in of electrical engineering. With the CRISP project, the web store is being completely redeveloped based on new cloud technologies.

As an architect and developer I am part of the Scrum team "Product", which deals with presentation of the products in the webshop.

Position: IT Specialist/Architect

<u>Contribution:</u> I support the customer with the realization of the webshop in the cloud environment. Therefore, I advise the customer in the creation and implementation of architecture concepts as well as new technologies like Kafka, MongoDB or Spring Boot and the introduction of DevOps approaches.

Examples of my contributions:

- Concept development and implementation of a system for the distribution of configuration settings in the cloud environment
- Participation in the Architecture-Chapter
- Implementation of a translation management tool
- Generation of PDF files with iText
- Performance optimization in connection with Kafka and MongoDB

techn. environment:

Java 11, AWS, Spring, Kafka, MongoDB, Vue.js, Nuxt, Git, Gitlab, Maven, IntelliJ, REST, JUnit, DevOps, Docker

04/2014 - 03/2019

60 months

Daimler

IT Architect for the Daimler MercedesMe project

<u>Project Description:</u> MercedesMe is a web portal based on the WebSphere Portal Server.

This project helps the client to drive car connectivity to an extend that was never seen before and could not be reached by competitors for years by implementing the solution

Page 2 of 4 Date: 18-Dec-2020



with cutting edge web technologies to attract the audiences of technophile people. End customers can view data of their vehicle online or they can invoke telematic services. In the context of this project I was as a developer and IT architect in a Scrum team. Since 2016, I have been the lead architect for the conceptual design and operation of microservices in the DevOps approach.

Position: IT Architect

Contribution: Through my experience as a software architect and my broad knowledge in Java and Web development as well as WebSphere Portal Server, I supported the client in realizing its vision in the field of car connectivity.

As a fullstack developer, I worked on a wide variety of topics in the front- as well as the backend. In addition, I was responsible for the development and the operation of various interfaces based on the technologies Kubernetes, Docker, REST and Angular and took on the role of the lead architect for the topic DevOps with Mircoservices. As a certified ScrumMaster I advised the client in questions about agile software development. Furthermore in the role the supplier

product owner I was the first point of contact for the customer and for the development team.

Examples of further contributions:

- · Concept development for a code modularization according to functional aspects
- Development and implementation of actions to increase the code quality
- Presentation and moderation of Sprint Reviews
- · Assistance with job postings
- Development of proof-of-concepts using new web technologies
- Creating architectural diagrams to improve documentation
- Optimization of the build and deployment process
- Promoting a "Continuous Improvement" mentality
- · Analysis and concepts to improve web security
- Improving Continuous Delivery

techn. env: Java 6, Java 8, JEE 6, JEE 7, WebSphere Portal V8/V9, JSR-286, WebSphere Application Server, DB2, EJB, JMS, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSP, JQuery, Git, Bitbucket, Maven, Gradle, RAD, RSA, Eclipse, JPA/Hibernate, JAXP, XML, JAXB, SAX, JDOM, WebServices, JAX-WS with SOAP, SOAPUI, Apache Axis, WebService Security, REST, Web Security, OWASP Top 10, Linux, Jira, Confluence, TestNG, Selenium with PageObject Pattern, Jenkins, Docker, Google Kubernetes, Wildfly, JUnit, Angular, Node.js, Nginx, Microservice Architecture, DevOps

Prior Experience

06/2013 - 02/2014 9 months

OTTO GmbH SEO-STAR

Project Description: Development of a portal application for the analysis and reporting of SEO data.

Contribution: Development and implementation of the system architecture, modeling class diagrams and processes,

implementation, creation of unit-tests, performance tuning in terms of dealing with large amounts of data and efficient processing logic, installation of the infrastructure: creating and configuring OpenStack instances, Postgres databases, Liferay portal, Nginx, Jenkins jobs etc.; tech. env.: Java 6, JEE 6, Liferay-Portal-Server, Spring, XML, JAXB, JPA/Hibernate, PL/SQL, JSF/PrimeFaces, JUnit, MySQL, Postgres, Git, Ant, Maven, Openstack, CentOS 6

01/2011 - 05/2013

OTTO GmbH

29 months

Support for development of the webshop

Project Description: Support for development of the webshop otto.de as part of daily business.

Contribution: Analysis, maintenance and development of the webshop in collaboration with product management;

techn. env.: Java 6, Intershop Enfinity, Spring, Oracle DB,

JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, JUnit, TestNG, XML, JAXB, JAX-WS with

Date: 18-Dec-2020 Page 3 of 4



SOAP, SOAPUI, Eclipse, Jenkins

02/2010 - 11/2010

10 months

IT service company

Set-up of the IT infrastructure, web application development

 $\underline{\text{Project Description:}} \text{The customer wanted support both in the set-up}$

of the IT infrastructure and in the

development of various web applications.

<u>Contribution:</u> My fields of responsibility were varied. I was active both as a project leader and software developer. My tasks were in addition

to setting up the IT infrastructure

(Creation of instances in the data center, application servers and many more) the coordination of staff and the conceptual design and

development of web applications (e.g.

for managing address and customer data); techn. env.:

Java, JEE, Eclipse, Java Server Pages, Java Server

Faces, JavaScript, Google Webtoolkit, JUnit, TestNG, JPA/Hibernate,

XML, JAX-WS, JBoss, SVN, Maven, Design Patterns, Visual

Paradigm (UML Tool)

06/2008 - 11/2009

18 months

Ewert Ahrensburg Electronics (EAE)

V.I.P. (Visual Intelligent Plant)

<u>Project Description:</u> V.I.P. is software for control and management of a newspaper printing plant. The customer wanted comprehensive

support in maintenance and development.

Contribution: Software development, conceptual design,

implementation of specifications, OOA / OOD, maintenance, testing, second-level support; techn. env.: Java, Java Swing, Java Applets, JMS, JDBC, Stored Procedures (SQL), MSSQL 2005, XML, XSLT, JDOM, JAXB, SAX, Ant, JBoss, Enterprise Java Beans (EJB 3), JPA/

Hibernate, Eclipse, CVS with MKS (Version control system)

02/2008 - 04/2008

3 months

Provider of travel expense accounting and travel management processes

TOPAS: Software for travel expense accounting

Project Description: Development of a Import-/Export-Moduls for

travel expenses data

Contribution: Conceptual design and development of an import/export

module:

tech. env.: Java, Eclipse, Java Swing, JUnit, SQL, Sybase, CVS

Other relevant information

Other job-related activities

During my studies I worked for many years as an assistant at the Institute of Mathematics at the University of Lübeck. I was an assistant for various mathematical lectures (analytics, probability and statistics, numerics, biomathematics) and led exercise groups.

Page 4 of 4 Date: 18-Dec-2020